<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Example Blog</title>
    <link>http://example.org/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Example Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 18:30:21 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MenuBerry</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/menuberry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 18:30:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/menuberry/</guid>
      <description>MenuBerry is a app for vegans to discover what to eat at restaurants.
I have been building MenuBerry part-time for the last year or so. It started as a hobby project that eventually grew over time. It is still in the early days, but it&amp;rsquo;s fully functional for people to use. Visitors can utlize the application by using it as a resource to find restaurants and vegan options, as well as sign up to receive updates plus contribute content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MACC Roofing</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/macc-roofing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 18:30:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/macc-roofing/</guid>
      <description>This is a project I did for a client that needed an online presence for his roofing business. I built him a static website using the GOlang Hugo generator, and hosted it on github pages. I than integrated it with Forestry.io to allow for a CMS like expeprience. He can now update content on the fly without having to pay a monthly fee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typing Speed Calculator</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/typing-calculator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 18:30:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/typing-calculator/</guid>
      <description>This is a simple words per minute typing calculator. I built it using the Volt framework, which specializes in running your Ruby code on the CLIENT as well as the server. I did not write a single line of Javascript, as Volt uses the Opal gem to compile your Ruby code to javascript. You can read about how I made this simple app here .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Valley Ruby Brigade</title>
      <link>http://example.org/projects/tech-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 18:30:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/projects/tech-valley/</guid>
      <description>This is redesign I did for a local User-Group of Ruby programmers. It was already using github pages for hosting so there was no need to mess with the back-end, I simply updated the bootstrap and took advantage of the responsive grid.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>